Okay, everybody. Welcome. This is the
June 24th regular Board of Finance
meeting June 24th, 2026.
We will go ahead and start with the
Pledge of Allegiance.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the
United States of America and to the
republic for which it stands,
[clears throat]
one nation under God, indivisible, with
liberty and justice for all. Liberty and
justice for all.
And I just admitted Matt separately. I
don't know
again, it may be because I'm logging in
as Town of Andover and I'll and I'll
next time around I'll try to make a note
to myself not to do that.
Um we were doing that when we didn't
have a town admin, so.
In any event, um right. So, looking at
the agenda here, we have uh round of
public speak and changes additions. Um I
do have a change addition, but we'll
start with public speak. I think the
only member of the public we have here,
you know, who's not a town employee. Oh,
no, we have two. We have Joanne and
Scott.
Um I'll go I'll I'll start with Joanne.
For public speak.
>> I'm all set. Just here to listen. Thank
you.
>> And Scott.
>> Me, too.
>> Very good.
Um Alicia, you're our treasurer, but if
you want to speak,
go ahead.
No, okay, you're all set. You're muted,
by the way. Okay, so um changes
additions.
I got a call yesterday at work um from
Caitlin Greenhouse, chair of the Board
of Education, regarding the status of
the bathroom project at the school.
There has been a substantive
development. So, I want to add
discussion of that as we can call it
whatever we want. Um probably as we'll
make the town administrator's report 4A
and we'll make update on school bathroom
project 4B. Liaison report, if you will.
My understanding is there was a meeting
was it this morning, Bill?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh regarding this.
>> Mhm.
>> So, um you know, Bill can kind of report
in and and I I chime in as needed. But
that's my proposal is to make uh town
administrator's report 4A and school
bathroom project update 4B.
>> Well, then you wouldn't need the
liaisons on it, too, right? You would be
>> No, that would just be calling it
some what
you know
>> Got you.
>> update.
Anybody uh
second that? Everybody okay with that
change?
I'll
>> I'll second it, Bill.
>> Okay.
Uh all in favor?
>> Aye.
>> Okay, looks unanimous. Thank you.
Very good.
Um
So, in the interest of moving along,
does anybody else have any changes,
additions, etc.
that they want to bring up?
Going once, going twice. Okay.
Town administrator's report. Matt,
you're up.
And you're
>> muted.
>> Hopefully we're not having technical
difficulties.
Hm.
All right. How about this? Why don't we
>> I got I finally got it off.
>> There you are.
There you are.
>> Sorry about that. I was uh
Um yeah, so Matt Streeter, my report. Uh
I did uh talk to uh Val today about the
uh
the
uh situation at the bathroom. I guess
that uh we'll be talking about that in a
little while.
Uh so, I know that there has to be that
there's going to be some uh pipes that
had some uh additional uh possible
asbestos wrap wrapping on them. I guess
we could talk about that a little later,
but there might be an additional cost
for that.
Uh as far as all the other things with
the uh administrator's report, uh
just knowing that the uh,
budget passed that the
tax collector was getting everything
ready to be sent out. The assessors
worked on the
the mill rate and I did submit a list of
the things that was working the previous
week. I don't I'm currently working on a
list of my to-do list for the past week,
but uh, a lot of it has to do with uh,
getting ready for the end of the fiscal
year, making sure that uh, we are filing
for reimbursement for certain grants,
making sure the grant projects are
moving along and uh,
that being said, I'm here to answer any
questions.
>> Okay, so I see it's about a page and a
half here in our packet.
Um, that you prepared. I guess this was
prepared originally for a board of
selectmen meeting.
Um,
do you want to go through it, Matt, just
briefly at an overview? Um,
typically that's what we would do.
But that's up to you, Rob. I don't know
if that's
Um,
>> I'm sorry.
>> Well, some of it is just is is fairly
basic, but um,
>> Yeah, it was really just a
it was just a sort of like a great shot
of everything that was going on. Um,
I did go over a lot of the items with
the select board at their meeting. Uh, I
just thought it would be good to have
you have uh, see you know, the same
situ- uh,
same thing I had reported to the select
board, but I am uh,
>> Okay.
>> that's jumping out at you and then in
the future I can just make sure that I
uh,
uh, prepare ahead of time that I can
give you a more updated because
obviously that's been a week and a half
since that one was uh, was put together.
>> Okay. Well, I mean some of these things
I think are probably um, more relevant
to select board. Like I I I'm a I'm a
little curious about the um,
you know, collective bargaining item,
but that's not really our bailiwick. Um,
so
if anybody else has questions, I'll I'll
I'll throw it out to the board, but I'm
just going through here. This all just
looks like kind of uh
You're getting your You're You're
digging in.
>> Yeah, that is correct. Uh
getting uh
and not only that, but I'm getting above
water. I think when you the first couple
uh
two to three weeks uh it really was like
a lot of things were going on. You were
dealing with the
you know, things with the budget and the
different referendums and town meetings
special town meetings and other meetings
that were going on. But now that things
have sort of
I can say calmed down, the waters are
uh clear clear and I'm getting to know a
lot of the people and how things are
working. So,
uh with that I can confidently think
that uh
every meeting moving on that I'll be in
a little bit better situation to you
know, tell you what things that are
going on and speak more intelligently
than I probably did at the first meeting
I was at.
>> [laughter]
>> I appreciate that.
>> Sorry, just as a
>> [clears throat]
>> just as an aside on your comment about
being participating in uh
or
not your responsibility related to
uh collective bargaining. You guys I
hope to get one of the members of the
Board of Finance on a committee.
>> Okay.
>> As we do negotiate with public works.
Um
salaries are the most
they're the biggest cost that we have as
a town. You guys should be engaged. So,
we got to get somebody on there. We got
to get an understanding of what it will
do to us in the future as to the
increases and you know, the benefit
items that we sit there and and give out
in collective bargaining. So, you guys
should be involved.
>> Absolutely.
>> What's the timing on that then, Jeff?
When would you need that person
designated
from our board?
>> Um
it would be nice if we could do it
tonight, honestly, because this is
something that we have to get to because
Matt, the the timing on that contract um
it really is July 1st, isn't it?
>> Yeah, it expires at June 30th. Uh but uh
you I have reached out and I have talked
to the
and not only the union steward but the
agent for uh ask me and uh they were
understanding that you know, with the
changes in the uh certain positions that
we had, especially the town
administrator position, that they uh
they had sometime back in January sort
of just sent out a like a uh unofficial
letter just saying, "Hey, we're this is
where we're at. Uh when you're ready to
move forward, we're you know, we're
ready." And they you know, the people
I've talked to the union uh members that
they're on they're understanding that
you know, this will be done in hopefully
short time. But we do need to get going
and it would be great as the the first
selectman said to get some
representation from the the board of uh
the board of finance so that we can
kind of figure things out and cuz this
this once we do this step, it'll be you
know, next year we have the next union
contract that's going to be expiring. So
we want to kind of uh plan out our
strategy as we move forward with these.
>> How many unions do we have? Is it two?
>> In the town we have two.
>> In as part of these contract
negotiations, does that involve as well
the payment in lieu of health insurance
issue?
>> Mhm.
>> And that's part of contract, right?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
All right. So I guess the question would
be uh because we you know, we get a
we'll come up with a board member
tonight. I think it's good idea and um
when do you think
>> When do you meet with the
>> that person would need to be available?
Like what when not when not in terms of
the next week, whatever, but the day of
the week, do you have any idea when
you're going to try to meet on this?
>> It would be to try and figure out mutual
times. So whoever we get, we would like
to try and I'm really available at any
time. So I can make my schedule
available. So really it'll be between
the first selectman,
uh the person for the finance and again,
whoever is representing the union.
>> Yeah. As as as I actually would like to,
um, since I work full-time,
I don't think I'm the right choice. Uh,
does anyone else on the board want to
throw their hat in the ring on this?
>> Just so everybody's aware,
it would be during the week. It would be
during the work day because the union
representative is not going to want to
do it at night.
>> It's kind of what I was thinking.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Did Kim were you interested? Is that why
you were
>> I heard Kim saying yes.
>> volunteer. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Fantastico. I'm I'm good with that. Um,
I don't know if anybody else, otherwise
we'll just
go ahead and thank Kim for her service.
>> Awesome.
>> Yeah, I was going to offer, but but I
saw her raise her hand.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, if if you want more than one
person, I'm happy to join in as well,
too. Whatever.
>> Thank you for that.
>> So, Kim can be the member of this
committee and kind of our liaison.
[snorts]
Uh, let us know how it's going and
>> Sure.
>> Fantastic. Thanks for taking that on.
Um, and I, you know, agreed that it's
good to have us all involved. Um,
when I said before,
not our bailiwick, I meant,
you know, it's it's more
the select board, but I like this I like
this approach.
Um, okay. So,
anything else on the town
administrator's report that people want
to
dig into? I mean, we've got a lot going
on.
Um,
is there any of I guess what I what I
would say, Matt, my question to you is,
in this list of various projects and
things that are going on, is there
anything in there that you would
highlight that
potentially has, um,
a budgetary impact where, you know,
we're still in the 25-26 budget. Is
there Is there an item on here that's
possibly going to be, you know, lead to
an overage or anything like that that
you would bring up?
>> I'm not thinking of anything overage. I
think I'm One One the things is really
just kind of making sure that all the
grant projects that we have, the bridge
project, everything that, you know, that
the funds are
somewhere out there and that, you know,
that we are moving forward to, you know,
use them. And there are some things that
possibly had been either some earmarks
that had a component that had a match or
uh and some that don't. So, I want to
make sure that if there is funds that
are out there that had already been
appropriated in the budget, I got to
kind of like see where they are cuz I
was told like uh there was a uh
I'm trying to think if there was a
parking lot uh that was
possibly talked about being done and the
money was put aside for it. And also
that there was possibly a roof for the
uh a building at the DPW that was
approved. Uh just to make sure cuz we'd
have to, you know, start thinking about
either whether we're going to have to,
you know, go put out an RFP for, like
say, for the roof project at the DPW.
Uh I don't I don't I Those are the
things I just really got to work on and
try to see
that make sure that there are as funds
available.
Okay. If there's things that are pushed
off.
>> Fair enough.
>> I have a question.
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> Can you talk Can you talk about number
six?
Um Matt set up on accounts and
procurement, processing invoices.
Can you talk about that item?
>> Sure. Part of it is that uh
uh I had to get put on the as accounts
and also I had get the authorization as
a procurement agent for the town for,
you know, certain things that when I
when I sign uh
either documents for certain vendors
that we have. Uh it's in the it's in the
charter, you know, that talks about uh
some of the responsibilities that the
town administrator has as a procurement
person. But it's really just making sure
that I'm put on some of these accounts
and that
uh I'm getting the invoices on them. A
lot of the invoices uh say,
hypothetically, say like Home Depot and
those bills, they're still coming in.
Some still say Robert Burbank, some are
saying Eric Anderson. It's really just a
procedural just kind of like making sure
that they're getting to the right place,
they're getting to the right email.
Things may be still going to
an old E. Anderson email instead of a
town administrator email or it's really
just making sure that everything payroll
for payables
which also say when I say procurement,
I'm thinking everything that we're
spending money on.
Most of the small stuff.
>> Thanks.
>> You're welcome.
>> If if you guys don't mind, I'll I'll sit
there and I'll go through a couple
things that Matt has here so you guys
are aware of what's going on.
So, um
Long Hill Bridge is moving forward. As
Matt said, we had work this week to sit
there and make sure that our grant um
reimbursement process is is smooth and
that we have all of our funding
uh all of the monies that we're
dispersing coming back to us as quickly
as possible. The Veterans Field project
is completed. There's going to be a
grand opening on the the uh the field on
July 1st. So, the committee for um that
field is working on a um a grand opening
and they're planning on it for July 1st.
It should be in the paper so that
everybody can sit there and
come down and see what a nice job
Christine Rondazzo and really Scott
Person did to sit there and utilize the
grant funding that we have.
>> A quick question, Jeff. Is that open to
the public yet or do we have to Is there
wait till the grand opening or can it be
used now?
>> Well, if you want to go down there and
play pickleball, have at it, my friend.
So,
>> I want to use the slide on the new
slide.
>> You can go to
>> The slides, yeah.
>> Yeah, as long as you make the weight
protocol, right? You know, there is a
weight limit. Um but yes, that that
project is is
completed. Um
The pavilion looks phenomenal. Um
I know that there were some um
contributions on top of that to put in
picnic tables into the pavilion. So, the
pavilion has six picnic tables. We have
four pickleball courts, and we have a
really nice playground that is ready for
use. It has been used, but July 1st is
the grand official opening for the town.
Um
And number [clears throat] five, you
have the diesel fuel system. You know,
we've had a problem with the fuel
system, the pump down there, the
software for the pump uh
uh
you know, finally quit. Uh that is going
to be something that we're going to deal
with in this fiscal year, but we're
actually not going to get it. It's going
to It's a six uh six seven week
uh
delay on getting the pump ready to go.
So, that's
a big That's going to get done.
And we need it because, you know, we
have to bill all of the uh
the entities that actually use diesel.
So, we have to bill RAM, we have to bill
AES, we have to bill
uh the fire department um
So, there's a lot of things that the
treasurer's office and public works have
been having to deal with it. We have
uh systems that needed to be upgraded.
So, we're doing that. Um
>> Hey, Jeff, just a quick question. In the
interim, if it's going to take six
weeks, what are we doing? What's the
backup?
>> They're doing it manually.
Rob, so we have to sit there and take
the information and do it manually. So,
um
It's a pain.
>> It's a pain.
>> And and really, the biggest problem in
in just so everybody's aware, the
biggest problem is the initial month
that it went down.
Um
we have to estimate some numbers. Now,
it's it's worked pretty well from what
I'm understanding is that the the buses
actually uh
record their fill-ups each time. So,
we're you know, we're going to be pretty
good on the school side.
And on RAM side, um but we're going to
have to make some estimates and get it
done. So, Lisa has been working on that.
>> Jeff, what is the hold up? Why does it
take 6 weeks to get that?
>> It's the piece of equipment. We're we're
actually getting a whole pump. It's not
just like a computer.
>> Oh, okay.
>> a whole new pump and a whole new system.
>> Got you.
>> Right?
Um
And so,
you know,
six, Matt has been set up as the global
administrator on the banking side.
Uh I sent out some information to Rob on
banking. Um one thing that's going to
occur on the town side is we have 24
bank accounts at the town. Um
21 of them are small little things.
We're going to consolidate all those to
get down to three bank accounts
>> Excellent.
>> so that we can sit there and uh
be able to manage this a little bit more
effectively. And and and really the goal
is to earn more money for the town.
Because if we take those bank accounts,
there's about $790,000
that's currently in those 21 accounts.
Those accounts are either earning 0%
interest or
0.1% interest. So, if we take those
funds and we move them into the stiff
account, we can earn 3.71 currently. So,
that's
what we're working toward getting that
done. That all those funds will be
transferred uh
by the end of this month. And just for
everybody to understand
I've had multiple conversations with the
auditor so that we're offset as far as
how we sit there and handle
um
uh the fund balances that are currently
in there. So, some of those funds are
funds like uh
the uh Norton Scholarship Fund or the
Moody Scholarship Fund. Those those
entities need to get the interest on
their accounts. So, we're going to try
to get them more interest, but we're
going to sit there and do that as a
manual calculation. So, the town has
um let's say 2 to 3 million dollars in
this fund and it earned 3% interest. And
then we're going to sit there and move
the 3% interest over to those charitable
funds.
Uh so, that fund balance keeps
escalating. But there's other funds that
don't that are getting the 0.01%
interest that don't need to get that
interest. It's really money for the town
to offset taxes. And if we can do a
better job in the finance department of
moving that money to the stiff account,
all the better.
>> Perfect. Agreed.
>> So, if we can do that, that's great. And
then uh grant administration, um Matt
has uh
like he said, he's been doing a a very
good job. And and Lisa and her group of
Brenda is the new town
uh assistant treasurer. Uh
you know, she's they're she's very good.
So, if you get a chance to go in there
and say hello to her, Brenda is is doing
a great job. Uh Lisa is doing a great
job. We're going to sit there and get
the grant. Uh Matt is working to make
sure that we get all of our
reimbursements on the Bunker Hill Bridge
project. Um that's first on the list.
And then we've made two payments on the
bridge for Long Hill. We'll get that
done. And the uh
steep grant for the playground will be
reimbursed also. And we also have
uh some other funding that we're getting
from the state related to that
playground. So, um
the biggest issue on my mind has been
reimbursement of all the funds that
we've put out. So, once we can get all
those money back, I'll be much happier.
>> Jeff, is there any uh update on the
firehouse?
Um
>> Well, if you I I
I gave Matt kind of the marching orders
of things that I would like to see done
and how I would like to see them done.
So, I'll go over them with you.
Um, the first is get all the grant money
organized. But then, as far as projects
go, uh, the next project that really
needs to be taken in is the generator
project at the town hall and this the,
uh, community center and the firehouse.
So, we're going to put the generator in
and connect up all three buildings. And
then, right after that, I want him to
get on to the kitchen in the the senior
center because you know, we have funding
on these different projects, so we want
to sit there and get some of these
things accomplished as quickly as
possible. So, it would be the kitchen at
the community center. And then, we need
to focus on the downstairs in the
community center. So, I asked Tess to
sit there and do, uh,
um,
get some feedback as to what we really
can do in that downstairs area. Uh,
then, Bill, it's gone to the firehouse
and getting the the, um,
facility for all of the the, uh,
vehicles
completed. That one might be something
that we end up having to come back to
you guys on. We have to determine all of
the financing issues related to that one
because, um,
the initial, uh,
plan that Eric had developed was for a
single
story building. That caused us some
problems, so we're going to we're
potentially have, uh, I have to look at
what we've done in the past as far as
what we tried to sit there and allocate
to that, but we're going to have to sit
there and work on that. And that one is
something I think we were going to
probably have to come back for, you
know, let's say 30 to 50,000 dollars,
but we need to get that project done as
well.
>> Wasn't there,
uh, something with the grant there
though we have to do certain work,
possibly at the museum or something like
that or spend some money somewhere else
to, you know, get that money, right?
>> I remember of windows being involved.
And window frames or something.
>> Well, there was a discussion Rob about
the front door and then the roof in the
back building. Um, but basically that
was um
uh you would never believe it, but the
old firehouse is in um
historical zone. And so because we
wanted to sit there and uh
tear down a
an eyesore, it's a historical zone and
SHPO required us to make some um
commit some dollars to another building
in town which Bill, that was correct. It
was the old town hall. And to be really
honest that this this board
along with the
the um Board of Selectmen, we should be
looking at that building
um
the old town hall now. So, I'm getting a
little off track, but the old town hall,
we should look at that building as um
you know, maybe a cultural center or
something else that we could do with it.
I know we have the museum there. I know
we have you know, uh events maybe once a
month, but it is something that that's a
nice little building and has historical
significance to the town. It's on a very
nice visible area for the community and
we should probably be as creative as
possible with that building. Uh I know
that Bill's wife is heavily involved in
that and um
she's talked about putting up um
a it's not a pergola.
>> A cupola?
>> Cupola, there you go. Like uh because if
you look in old small pictures that the
museum has, there was a cupola on that
building uh previously. So, certain
things that we should be doing there,
but we've got to finish the um
um
the the old firehouse as the as storage
for the vehicles and then the other
project that we need to sit there and
get our funding in place is for the
Percy Cook Trail.
So, we need to get that funding in place
and do that because that's that's
something easy that we can do to connect
the trail to the town complex.
And then the one that's just sitting
there that is going to be a little bit
more difficult and I told Matt is
something that we really have to work on
and even determine what we want to do
with it is
the connector that Eric had been working
on from the
from the bridge to uh
uh 2 3 up 316. So, that connector. But,
that is a a a
another problem. El El and then one last
one, sorry to bother you, but uh
the uh Wales um not Wales, the um Basola
Bridge project is something that's
coming up in the next 12 months. And so,
we have to get uh a bunch of easements
from the property owners down there.
>> I'm sorry, what bridge is that, Jeff?
>> The Zola Road. It's a
>> Oh, Zola, yeah.
>> The Zola is the culvert.
>> Culvert.
>> Yeah. And so, once we can do that, then
we should be uh
So, Matt's got a lot of physical
projects on his plate that we got to
help him with. But, that's the outline
of what I told Matt this week that we've
got to sit there and get accomplished.
>> Great.
>> So, I have a question.
Um with the Yeah, with the uh fiscal
year coming to an end, are there any
accounts that haven't been reconciled
yet
that we know of?
>> I'm not able to answer that question. I
That's probably something more for the
treasurer's office.
>> I mean, yeah, we would ask
>> Yeah, it's Lisa. Lisa is not here.
>> Are you talking about the grants
reconciliation?
>> No. No, just accounts. Bank accounts.
Yeah, bank accounts.
>> Uh I can tell you and there you go,
Lisa, you can answer it.
>> [laughter]
>> The general bank account, I'm just
finishing up May. Um
the STIFF account, you can see well,
when we were going to get to the budget
to actual, I was I'm just mention that.
The STIFF count um is going to be
pretty much on spot. Um you might have a
a surplus of like 10,000 in there. So,
that I can do fairly quickly.
Um as far as your other accounts,
um
not the grant accounts that Jeff is
talking about, but the liability
accounts, we're trying to get to those,
too.
Um we're getting there, um but it's a
long process cuz there's so many of
them.
>> Well, you're talking about two um
um
Louise bank accounts.
>> Yes. Yeah, I'm talking
>> accounts. All the bank accounts and
records.
>> Yeah, right.
>> All right. There are fund accounts that
that because of how they were done
previously,
uh
we made some adjustments and we we will
be able to provide you
uh out of the finance office those
uh by your next meeting.
>> Good to hear.
>> So, so what you also have to do for us,
and I mean, I have a vision of what I
think you guys should want to see. You
should want to see those funds because
now that the bank accounts are going to
get closed, those funds are just going
to be
uh balance sheet accounts. And so, you
know, reality is I had been asking for a
balance sheet for the previous treasurer
for years and I never really got it. So,
that's the one thing that I've been
asked Lisa to get done and we're going
to work together to sit there and get
the balance sheet together. So,
everybody can see the funds, everybody
can sit there and see what's uh
remaining in them and uh
>> So, just speaking for myself, what I
want to try to work on, and I was going
to at some point maybe meet with Matt
and and talk about this,
is not only would I like to be able to
see the the the funds kind of in real
time and as opposed to, you know, every
year at the audit,
but also
um
you know, as a town, we we I we could
put together a proper capital plan, town
school, the whole the whole nine, and
then we can line them up. If we have
funds where we know
where we're going to be spending money
that we've actually allocated, you know,
we we should have a document maybe that
links that up and and shows on the one
hand, here's the fund applicable, here's
the expenditure we expect for XYZ
projects.
And I
And I'm not sure if it should be on the
same document, probably not, probably a
different document. On the revenue side,
you know, there is there's money we
could that comes in from the state that
in in general in our budgetary documents
we've never displayed, things like town
aid road, things like that. You know,
some some of the grant money that comes
in that I would love it if we could,
going forward, work on displaying again
in kind of real time for the board so
that we can see
the you know, a trued up you know, this
is what we spend in road work a year.
You know, we load in
What it was it? $385,000
to the budget, then we take that and we
add town aid road, and then we use it on
X, Y, and Z.
So,
you know, things like that so that we
can we can get a fuller picture, a more
holistic picture of everything that's
going on both on the revenue and
expenditure side. So,
you know, that's maybe not as articulate
as I'd like, but that's why I why I was
thinking about sitting down with Matt
and just sort of hashing it out.
>> I I'm I'm in absolutely
>> Yeah.
>> I'm in I'm in agreement with you, Rob,
but I think the one guy that we got to
include in this is the auditor. So, at
our July 22nd meeting, you should be
prepared, everybody on your board,
everybody from the board of selectmen
that wants to attend, should be prepared
to ask him questions regarding that
because
>> Yeah.
>> I agree with you that that there are
specific grant dollars that should Town
Aid Road is the one from the town that
is just the only
I don't know Lisa, is there anything
else that I'm missing? Town aid road is
the one that's
>> Is the largest one. Yeah, and you've got
your steep and your low sip, but those
aren't anywhere near
>> Low sip small, but it's but still I want
it on there, yeah.
>> But but those are not um
>> The other ones are
>> Those are not consistent grants.
Um
I don't believe
>> fluctuates?
>> Um I think
>> Well
The board of Ed has I I mean we get that
list from the state. We just got to
review it.
>> Yeah, but
>> Categorize it better.
>> Correct, but from the town side, the
town aid road money is consistent and it
should be put what we should do is put
the town aid road in our income
>> Yep.
>> calculation
>> Absolutely.
>> and our spending on the roads on the
expense side. So we all are aware of
what we're doing. So
I I 100% agree with that and
you know
>> That's what I follow too.
>> Yeah, [snorts] I'm in with the agreement
with that as well.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't think there's any really other
Rob any other consistent grants.
>> Smaller.
>> And that and that was the other
conversation I want to have and by the
way I
was going to bring that up too that our
next meeting we have our auditor. So
this is exactly the time to to talk
about this stuff with with the auditor
on how to handle it. How to how do
properly handle tracking
our inconsistent grants.
Our conditional grant, whatever you want
to call them. You know, grants we we get
for a specific issue or grants that
fluctuate or what have you. How how is
the best way for us to approach that and
you know
receive and disseminate that
information. So that that's another one
on my list.
>> Yeah, I think that you have the smaller
consistent grants. You have the one for
historic preservation. You have the
library one I believe there's one for
that. And then you had you just had a
$10,000 one for community center.
So, I I'm thinking the library and the
first one are consistent, but they're
small.
>> They're the
Yeah, I mean
>> Mhm.
>> And it just so just so everybody on this
board understands how the finance office
is doing this right now is
if there is a grant come that comes in,
so
the community center grant
that came in that community center grant
was specifically allocated towards the
software that that was being purchased
and has some impact related to the fine
of the transportation program.
So,
the treasurer's office and Lisa correct
me if I'm wrong just so I I don't want
to say the wrong thing, but
that money would then go in and offset
the expenses for for that specific line
item.
>> Right.
>> So, so
the community center might spend
$15,000, only have $5,000 budgeted, and
then the grant money comes in and
reduces the expenditure. I do not like
that at all, like in any manner.
But, um
I personally think we should sit there
and have a grant
income account, and then under the grant
income account should be sub accounts
and say, "Here's this, here's this,
here's this, here's this." So, you see
it, and then at the end of the the year
make the adjustments on the financial
statement to get the audited statements
to work.
That's what I believe, but you got to
ask the auditor cuz
you know, find
>> There's the registrar's Yeah, the
registrar's grant grant was
>> Yeah.
>> That was difficult, too, cuz that pays
for salaries.
>> Yeah.
I mean, and and that that fund
accounting is a really, um
uh odd
accounting world, all right? And so so
to me, I almost would rather sit there
and look at it going, "Okay, here's
here's your income streams and your
income sources. Everybody's aware of
what the income streams are and then
you're spending money and then at the
end you make the adjustments for the
audited financial statements to reduce a
given line item for an expense.
That would be better
visually for your board and for the rest
of the town to digest um
rather than doing things like has been
done for years and years and years with
town aid road where
you take the grant and put it in and
offset spending that you've done on the
road and then that that fund does keep
the balance rolling, but it would be a
lot easier to see if it was done in a
different way.
>> Mhm.
>> I agree.
>> I agree, too.
>> I've been that's been kicking around in
my head for a while. So, um I think it's
great if everybody thinks about that for
our next meeting.
Uh
and we'll chew it on it with the with
the order.
>> Sounds good.
All right.
Um
So, uh before we
move on the agenda, if is there anything
else in this uh administrative report
that anybody else wanted to
ask about, dig into?
Or shall we move on to uh
our report on the school situation?
>> Uh just uh just so you
Manigan here. Uh
that uh I I
I was remiss to say talk about like you
know, we did have the new assistant
treasurer start. I think we would we did
have a New England Wetlands agent start.
We have a lot of you know, some projects
that you know, we're trying to get going
with that. Uh we are doing interviews
for the assistant community center
coordinator starting tomorrow.
Uh we have posted for a uh new uh public
buildings custodian.
And uh we are also posted for a transfer
station attendant. So, I think that you
know, we have some other positions that
are are coming on. I think that other
than that, I I we're things are pretty
stable, which is good to say. We have a
lot of new people, but I don't I'm
glad to say that, you know, I I'm
confident that we are going to be have
some of these positions filled, and
I will definitely keep you informed, and
hopefully by the uh
the July meeting, when we meet with the
order, that I'll have further
information for you.
>> I will say it was quite noticeable that
we don't have our um
our cleaning crew that we had in the
past. Um
The couple did a great job. I was in
there a couple times over the last
couple weeks, and the amount of dirt and
dust and straw and leaves
on the carpet was just embarrassing.
Um but hopefully we do get someone to
fill that position quickly.
>> Um
just just, you know, and then uh
Sorry. Sorry. You're 100% right, Bill.
And and we got Matt will we'll work
we're going to work on that. Um a couple
things I I I
should have brought this up. Um
Um
We
uh did offer and did um agree to a
3-year contract with the uh community
center director. So, for all of those
you didn't know, that that position uh
is going to stay the same. And also um
we had two resignations from the Board
of Selectmen.
Um so, I know that the members of the
Republicans that are here and and that
their town committee met, but
uh if you have any
anyone that wants to sit there and put
forth for
uh one of the openings, uh please let it
be known out there in public.
>> And I think I know the answer to this
question, but I'll ask it anyway, since
you didn't mention uh who were the two
people that resigned?
>> Uh Jeff Murray and Carol Lee.
>> That's what I thought. Okay, thank you.
>> So, has the uh town administrator's
contract been
um approved as well?
>> Good question.
The answer to that is no.
We had
a special meeting in place.
Um
Just so everybody knows the the reason
for the delay on that is
related to um
um
retirement
contribution, how we do it.
Um
The MERF is a is one option and there's
a 457, which is another option.
And we were supposed to have that on an
agenda for a special item, Louise, and
that meeting was canceled.
So, one of the members who was going to
attend
um
couldn't.
So, we only had two members at that
meeting and that was also a meeting with
um
the Hop River Homes
board um because there is a um
a tax credit that has been granted to
them for
uh 40 years.
And
it's a question of is it
should the town continue to do that?
It's it's 10 to 12,000 dollars a year
and should they should we do it based
upon
um
what is getting done for
the community.
Um
>> Do we know how many residents are
actually Andover residents that live
there?
What's the integer?
>> We asked that question, Bill, and the
question that I really asked was more
along the lines of do do Andover
residents get priority? So, if an older
resident who has
come upon hard times or wants to sit
there and downsize, would they get
priority on the facility? And the answer
is no. So,
it's basically USDA run
property and USDA has has a list and so,
it's a it's a it's not as simple as this
these are all positive things that
happen for the community. It's It's a
low-income housing it provides a service
to the
geographic community and um
you know, it's
it's a question. Where where What we
asked really is
the softball field was always the ticket
in my mind. You know, we used to we
leased the softball field for a for a
dollar and that was but we have no
sports in town. So
we don't have a softball program. We
don't utilize that field at all. So the
question was could we do something
creative with that? And so that's what
we're trying to think about doing and
the Board of Selectmen has to decide
what they're going to do with the tax
credit.
We didn't vote on it. So
>> Interesting.
>> Thanks, Jeff.
All right.
More information there.
Um
so [clears throat]
per the amended agenda 4B
is the the bathroom issue. Uh as I
mentioned, Caitlin called me about it,
but Bill probably has um more detail
than I do. So I'll turn it over to him
regarding this uh discovery of asbestos
around the piping.
>> So the good news is that all of the
um
demolition is done.
So whatever's going to be discovered has
been discovered. So at this point
there's a few things. There's the
asbestos.
They have a contractor picked out to um
do the remediation. There are There was
some contracts I guess that were a
little bit cheaper when they went out
for price.
But the way this thing works with the
state is each contractor has is a 10-day
waiting period that you have to get to
the state. So if you select a different
contractor other than the one that we
are selecting and already submitted to
the state, it would keep pushing the
project out further.
Uh so it was decided because of the
small amount of money that they would go
with the contract they've already chosen
because the date it's already been filed
with the state with that contractor and
so things will move forward quicker.
Um just stand where we are with that.
There was also some issues where they
thought there was a chase in the wall
that they could use. That chase is not
there that they have to build.
Uh some urinals have to be moved about 6
in to the right from where they were
originally planned and along with that
there's some small electrical changes.
So all of these are change orders that
will cost um
will cost the town probably around
$30,000,
but we won't really know the exact
extent of of those changes until the end
of the project. But because
the demolition's done,
they don't expect any more change orders
or any more surprises uh to come out of
the project. So they feel pretty
confident that that's that's the end of
the change orders right there.
Um so unless there's any questions on
that, but like I say um they're looking
somewhere around $30,000 for all of
those changes.
>> Yeah, Katie Katie said something like 25
to 30 to me. Yeah, and and you know,
just to chime in here,
one of the issues with the timing is if
you push out the project much, you run
into the school year start. Right. So
they're sort of under the gun with that.
Um the asbestos issue just you know, I I
I'm tangentially involved in such things
through my work.
It is what it is. It's unfortunate. It's
unlucky. Uh but you have to deal with it
and as I understand it, you know, you're
in a school,
right? Uh the state is going to want
that out of there for sure.
Um deep is going to want that out of
there. So they got to do what they got
to do is really what it boils down to
and and unfortunate. Um
but I I assume that once the
once that comes through
uh we can have a meeting regarding
releasing, you know,
whatever the final additional cuz we we
released 220
what the final additional is that we
need to add there. Now, in
in order to keep us up to speed, one of
the things I asked Caitlyn for was
I guess um Eric Sanderson is kind of
running oversight on the whole thing and
he's writing up reports. And I said,
"Look, the next report, the one that
talks about this, can you get that to
the Board of Finance, please?" So, we
get a copy and we can all see it.
Um his write-up of what happened when
they opened up everything
and what they found. So, that we're not
you know, when the request comes in,
everybody's kind of had a chance to look
at it, digest it, understand it as best
we can. Um
I thought that would help
for down the road.
That's all I've got.
>> Can [clears throat] I ask that those
reports go to the town administrator?
Because Matt, did you get that report?
>> I have not I don't believe I've seen
that. No.
>> I will um I will I will ask Caitlyn to
include Matt as well.
>> Okay. And then Bill,
um
were you part I know you were part of
the committee, but did the committee
have another meeting or was this you
just showing up or this is
>> no, they have a weekly uh update and
Eric Eric Sanders Eric Sanderson, who's
oversight
uh for us, he's on that meeting as well
as the the contractor that we're using
and uh Caitlyn and Val and myself. So,
it's a once-a-week meeting on Wednesday
morning 8:30 and I'll be going to all of
those meetings every week so I can keep
you guys up to date on, you know,
everything as it progresses.
>> Okay.
>> But that is a weekly man- uh meeting.
>> Is it a Is it a Zoom meeting or is it a
>> Yes. Uh it's a Teams meeting.
>> Teams meeting?
>> Yeah.
>> Um can you uh make sure that
>> Yeah, I'd like to get on that.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay. I'll talk to Caitlyn, make sure
that the invitation goes to Rob. Did you
Was that you?
>> No, that was Matt.
>> Oh, that was Matt. Matt, I'm sorry.
Matt, I'm sorry. Matt.
And
selectman, okay.
I'll make sure you guys both get that.
Anybody else?
>> No, just Matt.
>> No selectman. No selectman.
>> Just just Matt.
>> We don't We don't want to sit there and
and and overstep our bounds.
Matt Streeter
>> Okay, just Matt then.
>> Yeah.
>> Very good.
>> Are members Are members of the committee
able to go in and like have
I don't know, weekly walk-throughs or
maybe not weekly, but
>> Yeah. Um
they said I was able to go in if I want
to see the work. I'm not sure, you know,
I I'm sure I have to give get permission
cuz you have to have a hard hat on. You
have to notify the contractor you're
coming on site and all that kind of
stuff, but Caitlin and Val both said,
you know, I was welcome to go in there.
So, if there's somebody that wants to go
in there, I'm sure if we ask you know,
Caitlin or or Val, we just have to get
permission from the contractor cuz they
own that site when it's being
you know, worked on right there. They
have to know who's on and off the site
and all that stuff. So,
um yeah, but they said absolutely I
could go in there. So,
>> I was thinking maybe
I was thinking it might be appropriate
for Matt to be able to pop in every now
and then. That's all.
>> Yeah, I'm
I'm afforded the opportunity. I've
talked to to Val and she was going to
show
She gave me the progress. She showed me
pictures, but
uh one of the things as far as uh you
know, the public going in there, when
they're doing this
remediation as Bill was mentioning
>> Nobody goes in there.
>> No Nobody there Well,
A, no kids can be in the building and I
guess there is some sort of uh
summers program that goes on and is
outside.
>> summer camp
>> Yeah, the summer cool Yes, and then if
they used to use the bathrooms and
they're not allowed in there,
uh they they can use the community
center of the town hall. But adults or
anybody over 18 can be, but it usually
it's it's just wise that, you know,
while they're doing those type of
projects,
they do a pretty good job of
to try to limit it any extra people from
being in the building, but
I can definitely at some point set up a
time and you know, with anybody members
of the finance committee and
the school administration if they want
to just get a
I'm sure as Bill said walks walk through
when it once it's a little bit safer.
>> There was a bunch of pictures too that
the contractor did share this morning.
So I mean if there's any pictures of the
work that's been done in the demolition,
you know, the pipe, the lack of the
chase, you know, where the location of
the urinals are going to be, you know,
he took pictures of everything and so it
made made for a very good meeting this
morning. We could ask questions. We
could understand exactly what was going
on. So I'm sure if anybody wants to see
those pictures too, I could always ask
that they be forwarded along too.
>> Bill, can I ask a stupid question?
>> No stupid questions.
>> What's what's a chase?
>> Oh, so lots of times like
the best way I can describe it is I have
a old condo in Newport and it was built
before water, electricity and sewer. So
they build these little walls might be
like 8 or 12 inch in a corner of a
building where they use it to run pipes
and wires up and down from one floor to
the next. So there's like heating pipes
and water pipes and sewer pipes and
you'll you'll see this little jog in the
wall and that's just to house those
pipes or wires. So they call it a chase.
>> I was wondering what it was. I was
wondering if
>> Thank you.
>> [laughter]
>> Going up I guess they they thought there
was a chase there that's not there. So
they're going to create one.
>> Going up is ventilation.
>> Yeah.
>> As much as anything. So
Bill um
Eric Sanderson is our
our supervisor our super on the project,
right?
>> Construction manager, yeah. I guess you
call him.
>> Construction manager. All right. And
so he's he's participating in the weekly
meeting.
>> Yes.
>> All right. And then just so I
understand, what was the what was the
cost for that?
Anybody?
>> Um all together everything was $30,000.
The way I see it um that including
>> No, no, no, no.
You're talking asking about what Eric's
role cost.
>> Yeah. Eric's role.
>> Oh, Eric's role.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> I
I don't have it off the top of my head,
but I can get that for you, Jeff. I I
don't know what that Whatever it is is
well worth it. He's
>> No, no, no. I I
>> Yeah.
>> You know, he's having weekly meetings
and he can provide reports to the to the
>> Yeah.
>> to everybody who's interested, that is
positive.
>> Okay. Do you want me to get that cost
for you though?
>> Oh, I I just think the whole the board
should know. I I would like to know.
>> I have a I I honestly I think we talked
about it, but I can't remember the
number.
>> We did. We talked about it a couple
months ago and I for some reason between
8 and 12,000 is
>> I was going to say I know it's sub 20.
>> That's not a lot. I have a I have 11 in
my head.
>> What?
>> Okay, so somewhere in there.
>> That sounds right.
>> you're pretty darn close.
>> we can hunt it down.
>> Yeah.
>> I had 11 in my head.
But but from the town side, right? Just
include get Matt included so that when
somebody needs to ask a question or has
needs information,
he can at least
provide it to anybody who's asking.
>> Absolutely.
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
Yep. It's good. We do we do need to get
Matt involved in everything.
Um So, anyway, that's the deal. That's
the situation.
Uh
Think the sooner we talked about it, the
sooner we got info on it, the better.
>> I have a question on that.
>> Yes, go ahead.
>> If by chance
everything doesn't get done by the time
the school starts,
what's what's plan B?
>> Um well, see there's there's
there's the penalties
um the contractor. Financial penalties
and they're they're pretty heavy if he
doesn't finish the project on time.
Um there's a word for it, I can't it's
escaping me, but anyways, um
they're going to finish on time. That's
why they're going with the contractor
they first selected because there's a
10-day period for the state. Um that's
why that was important, and um
where they are right now and what
they've said today is they don't see
this
uh
pushing it out, Louise. So, I don't I
know that's not the answer you're
looking for. I don't know what the
contingency plan would be
if it actually wasn't done, but at this
point they're still saying the project
will be done.
Um I think they said the week of the
20th of August or some I forget the
exact date, but
it's still scheduled to be on time.
But, I don't know what plan B is,
Louise. I can always ask that question,
too.
>> Yeah, just curious.
>> Yeah.
I am, too.
>> Yeah, I mean, that's that's a that's a
that's an ugly scenario, so I think
they're just going to work really hard
to avoid it.
>> They're they're going to do everything
in their power to make sure they finish
that on time.
>> I'm sure I'm sure they will. Yeah, I'm
sure they will.
>> It's it's a financial hit to them if
they don't.
>> Yeah.
>> Costly.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> It's per day. For every single day, it's
a it's a pretty uh hefty hit, so.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Uh
in the interest of moving along, uh the
next things on our list
here is budget to actual. It's old
business. We're going to go through our
usual
you know, budget to actual, check
register
uh review.
Um anybody
chime in uh if and when you you see
something as as you
you know, if you've gone through it
already, great. Um you know, there are
some things on here I think
we've seen we've talked about in the in
the past as to why they might be over or
what have you. Um but, if anybody has a
question,
um you know, Lisa you can and Matt can
help us figure it out.
>> Like I said, I looked through it today
and
I think most of the ones that were, you
know, jump out at you
we've already talked about. So, but I'm
not sure if anybody else saw anything
new.
>> I had a question at the very end cuz I
just can't remember. What What is the
ask my accountant?
You know, we talked about I just can't
remember.
>> We inherited that.
We inherited that. So, um, and in the
chaos that it's been since I came in
January, we've put a couple things in
there and
we are going to review it um
and put it in the proper place, but
sometimes
when we've
moved along to get things going, um,
that's a temporary spot until we can
like allocate like
the fuel bill for $3,000. It's just like
where there's others we have questions
where to apply
like we've said, where to apply a fund
money or something like that, but it's
going to be resolved, but those those
that's something that they were using
before. It's a temporary spot. It will
be allocated before it by the end of the
year.
>> It's really like ask Lisa where this
goes.
>> Yeah.
>> Where does it go?
>> Or ask the accountant. I mean, it's just
like the real auditor and say, "Hey,
should this be like we're talking about?
Should this be revenue? Should this be
applied against expenditure?" Um, you
know, like
you were saying with the the community
service grant and then the bill that
came in for, you know, the um
for the transportation. It It's a
temporary spot.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
I would say
I just want to say the interest income
for the staff, that is only reconciled
up to February and I I looked quickly
and we have another 15,000 coming in for
March and April and probably
close to that. So, we will reach that
revenue and have a little bit more than
what we are expecting for budget.
Um the thing that is most over is legal.
Um so, that's something that we'll have
to contend with. The only other thing
that's really really over that are
salaries, but there's some that are
really under.
So, they kind of offset each other. I
haven't really figured out if
one way or the other
they're up or down.
But, you've got like five that are a
little bit over and you've got four that
are under.
So,
>> Some of that's the turnover, right?
We've got, you know, people helping out
their replacements or what have you.
>> Yeah, I mean you're over, you're under,
you're over in the town clerk assistant,
but you're under in town clerk. Um
you're over, you know, in snow and in
temp public works, but you're under in
regular public works.
You know, so these things like you're
over in elections,
um but you're over in registrar, but
you're under in elections.
Um
so, they kind of the only one that I
can't see any coverage for is the
community center.
I I don't know where that might come
from.
The other ones kind of offset each
other.
But, that and the legal are the things
that that I see that um are a little out
of balance.
>> Well, if memory serves, we have 48,000
in contingency left worst comes to
worst. Not that I want to tap that, but
>> Right.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> I will say we um just to update you like
I did with the um Board of Selectmen,
we did have some um
the problems with someone
tried to handle the bank account to you
know, got into our email. That's been
taken care of. Um
we updated the QuickBooks cuz I was
worried about that.
We initiated the ADP last week. We're
working out the kinks in that.
Everybody's coming forward and asking
about their balances, so we're real busy
with that.
Brenda has been great. Um it's going to
take time.
She'll learn municipality, but that's
going good. We'll be glad when the fuel
pumps are done.
Um I'm still trying to get together a
accounting class per se
cuz I think there's a lot to be learned
by a lot of people as far as W-9s, how
you we're going to start using purchase
orders,
um approvals, account numbers.
Um the auditors, we will probably start
the next one um middle of August cuz
they've already signed up. They already
asked me about that.
Um you know, and we're working on the
funds and the grants like Jeff was
talking about. So, we're very very busy.
So,
>> I hear [snorts] you.
>> Yep.
>> Lisa, have you talked any more or have
you done anything about payroll? You
were talking about getting a payroll
>> system company.
>> I did ADP. We initiated it last week.
>> Oh, you did. Okay.
>> Yes.
Yes.
Yeah. Um and it had, you know, some
glitches um but we're working out and
the employees have been asked to start
using their phone instead of the time
clock.
>> Oh, good.
>> And I had one person go online and try
and use it and she succeeded, but no one
else has attempted yet. Um but we'll get
there. We'll get there. I think
everybody will love it once they get it
cuz they can get their W-2, they can get
their pay stub.
Um the reporting is much better to me
than QuickBooks.
The glitches are probably too from they
said converting from a QuickBooks
instead of versus Paychex or PrimePay or
another payroll company is always a
little bit more difficult than like
another payroll company, so.
>> Yeah.
>> But it is
Lisa was the cost more for doing that?
To to run the payrolls because of the
new system?
>> Because of QuickBooks?
>> Yeah. No. No, before QuickBooks going.
>> it is a little bit more cuz remember we
talked about it in budget season. We
were already paying $100 a month for
Intuit and $200 a month for the time
clock. Those are both going to go away.
Um so this is
a little bit more than that. The other
thing was
they quoted it more on 35 to 40. We have
49 employees. We have we had 54 to start
before I took some off that had quit, so
that's another reason I wanted to go to
a payroll company is because it's it's a
lot. I I think a lot of people don't
understand there's a lot of election
workers. There's a lot of library
workers. There's public work workers.
There's town hall workers. You know, the
list goes on and on. There's there's
selectmen get paid. Everybody has to be
initiated on payroll. Everybody gets a
W-2.
So it it's a lot more I think than is
realized, so I think it's a better fit
for that many employees.
>> So if we're over that number that they
quoted us on, they might charge us a
little more cuz we're going to be over
>> It's it's $3 a paycheck, but
I mean you look at a lot of people get
paid [clears throat] once a year,
quarterly,
twice a year. So those are the ones that
we didn't count on
um that are like coming out of the
woodwork now to tell me that I owe them
on July 1st and I'm like, "Who are you?"
>> [laughter]
>> So
>> Oh, you owe me monthly salary.
>> basic ones are probably 40 a week that
we pay and we had quoted on that. But
whenever they input all 50 of them,
um they were like, "Well, this is a
little more than you told us." And I'm
like, "Well, I didn't know either." So.
>> Let's see who we can get rid of.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, I think some are so small that
they really could use a 1099 instead of
being on payroll. If they only get paid
once or twice a year, and now the
threshold is going up to 2,000 instead
of 600.
I mean, you know, I don't know. If that
small,
do they really need to be on payroll?
>> Right.
>> Mhm, so.
I don't know.
>> Something to keep an eye on moving
forward.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Yep.
>> Well, thank you, Lisa.
>> You're welcome.
>> Thank you.
All right, so um unless there's anything
further on the if you got if if anybody
has anything more on budget actual or
check register,
uh
let's talk about them now. Otherwise, um
we still have this
>> [laughter]
>> little item on our
old business that I feel like we've been
punting on for months and months now
because the budget cycle was more
important.
Um
and I'm I'm hoping I'm remembering it
correctly, the donation request thing.
>> Oh.
>> Uh you know, the request I I think this
was a Diane Grenier question.
>> Diane Grenier.
>> Yes, sir.
You know, does the town have a mechanism
to take in a
donation and and
deal with that. Now, I think at the time
one of the things we said was we're not
sure, we don't have a treasurer right
now. And we have too many accounts as it
is, right? We're trying to consolidate
our accounts and track our funds better.
So, I guess what I'd say is I mean,
might be inclined to punt again, but at
some point, Lisa, maybe we could have a
chat about
that if there's a mechanism if there's a
way of doing it that would be
appropriate. Maybe the auditor even.
>> I was just going to say, maybe you
should bring that up to the auditor.
>> Okay.
>> Because it's hard because
you know, you can't count I mean
>> But punt punt again because it all comes
down to process.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, well, it all comes down to
>> [gasps]
>> how
the money is received. I mean, listen,
the treasurers in the finance department
can't sit there and get
It's hard when you sit there and you're
bringing cash in and you're asking the
finance department to count cash and
deposit it. So, if I would ask you a
punt until we can come up with a process
that will work for the finance
department to not make it difficult on
them and to also take the money that the
residents are willing to sit there and
put to good use for the community. So,
we have to do it.
We're just not prepared right now to
come up with the right process.
>> For sure. And I don't want to make it I
don't want to do anything that's going
to add to the load right now. Um you
know, I want I want Lisa and um I'm
sorry, who who was our second
>> us to say Brenda, Lisa
>> and Brenda.
>> Brenda. I would like Lisa and Brenda to
have room to breathe
>> Yeah.
>> and settle in and catch up before we
say, "Oh, here. Here's a little boutique
thing uh for you to do." Uh no, I just
want to it's on there and I wanted to
just briefly chat about it. But I think
Aston answered for now. I think it's
down it's down the list of of
priorities, but it's definitely
something I'll put on the list to
at least bring up to the auditor, see
what he thinks um next month. Uh Liz, go
ahead. What's up?
>> Uh I will also tell you
I spoke to Diane Granier and I if I'm
remembering correctly, I think she found
a way
to do what she wanted to do with the
donation. Um I'm trying to text her
right now to say, "Am I remembering
things remembering this right?" I think
she found a mechanism to do a memorial.
>> She did, right?
>> She did it through the Hartford Public
Giving, but that's still
>> still doesn't answer for anybody
>> for you know, it was a one-shot
>> Well, she she did it because she really
wanted to get it forward. So she did it
for the
Hartford
you know, for public giving fund.
Um
But we have to do we have to figure it
out. It's not like it can't be done.
It's just how creative are we? How do we
make people understand this is the
process if you'd like to do it, this is
what you have to do and we make it as
easy as possible in the finance
department. And because there's also the
other part about this which is
you got to handle Well, let's say Diane.
She wants certain uses of her fund and
she wants the town to manage those uses
of the fund. It then becomes another
side of the whole problem and we have to
sit there and do that. So like right now
>> Like Norton or something it says it has
it has
>> And in the Norton the Norton funds are
charitable organizations and they were
established
100 years ago. So we just have to do a
better job and it's just something that
there's other priorities right now in
the finance department. We get through
that and we can get back into the how do
we do it?
First thing we have to do is get Lisa
out of the office
and get to a more reasonable timeline.
>> Yeah, yes. Get it
Get her back to semi-retirement.
>> Yes, well we we have
>> and my mom.
>> [laughter]
>> Understood and uh completely agreed. So
um yeah, I mean I'd like to move on to
the tax collector's request here. The
new business 6A
the um
>> Suspense report.
>> The suspense list. Yes, thank you.
Um I was scrolling and I lost the page.
Yes,
if memory serves this is a annual thing
uh the tax collector goes through. They
takes a look at
our our who's in arrears and you know,
as you see if you read the letter here,
you know, this is
for the most part this is people who are
either deceased or we can't find them.
And therefore highly unlikely to be a
collected although as she notes every
once in a while we get a little bit
uh collected but um I assuming this is
this is before us for the board to okay
it. Uh so you know, if anybody wants to
make a motion to accept to approve sorry
the tax collector's proposed suspense
list uh
I'm I'm okay with that.
>> I'll make a motion to approve the
suspense list
as presented
by Kate Fuller.
>> Dated June 22nd, 2026. Do we have a
second?
>> I'll second that.
>> Thank you, Louise.
Very good. Liz motions, Louise seconds,
any discussion? Further discussion?
No?
All right, call for a vote.
>> Sorry, I I have I have one I have one
question just for
>> Sure, Jeff.
>> Is this is this um
is this personal property taxes or is
this vehicle taxes? I mean, what what
are you looking at? Just so we're aware.
>> I would assume I all right, I I
shouldn't say I shouldn't assume things
but uh I would if you look at the um the
list itself it looks overwhelmingly
uh to be property to be houses.
Um
>> It can't be houses.
>> Or at least tied to houses but then in
the amounts some of the amounts are very
small. So it's possible it's probably I
would I would expect it would be
inclusive of all outstanding but
unlikely to be collected
uh property taxation.
>> Yeah, it's hard to know what what they
are.
It could be
>> cuz there's addresses there's addresses
listed but there's doesn't actually tell
you if that's their
you know, their car tax or their house.
>> It just tells
why she's put it on this list. I mean
some of these items are
really really old like I thought I
thought I saw one
I thought I saw something from 2016. Did
I see that or did I imagine that?
>> No.
>> Well I mean there's one that's there's
it starts with 2012. Um
>> Well I see see that one that one Rob you
can tell is personal property because of
the PP. So 07 PP personal property. It
says I'm business. So I'm assuming that
a lot of this is vehicle taxes and
they're
>> Are they license plate numbers under
like are those license plate numbers on
phone under their address?
>> There you go. I got I've seen now I like
it. We're thinking
good job.
>> Yeah that that makes sense.
>> Now that makes sense. So so those are
vehicles. So even if someone's even if
someone's deceased
I guess the car would go somewhere
anyway. But it doesn't matter. I I they
always just for my mind I wanted to know
what kind of taxes it was. So yeah
Heather is right. That's that's that's a
a license plate on a lot of them. So a
lot of the deceased ones it's a license
plate number it looks like.
>> Yeah.
I agree. And then number and the amounts
make sense.
>> Yeah like if that Boston one so let's
say the fourth one there the thousand
and sixty-six dollars.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah that looks like a a lot the
property map and block.
Like 1917.
>> It it also appears twice.
>> Because they're different years.
>> They're maybe different years. Yeah so
three times.
>> One says yeah so I see
so that's been starts off at yeah 2018
2019.
>> Oh yeah that's it's on there.
>> And so so
my question and Matt this would be
something you guys can approve this
because it's still collectible if you
read the letter it's
>> Yeah she's not giving up on it but
>> Matt like that thousand and sixty-six
dollar one there should be a lien placed
on that property.
>> Exactly.
>> And and I'm not sure that she's telling
us that there's been liens placed on
those, but that would be in my head what
the the town would want to do.
So,
like I get when somebody's, you know,
unable to locate it, I I don't think you
should be able to re-register the same
car without paying the taxes, but maybe
that's what's happened. But on the on
that thousand anything that's like it's
the same woman or same person on Boston
Hill Road
>> Yeah, Boston Road.
>> multiple times on this, it's probably uh
10% or half of the total
>> Half of the total is probably 10 grand.
>> So, um
Yeah, I just wanted to know what you
thought about that.
>> I'll try to get an answer for the next
meeting.
>> Yeah, and we can I mean, I can ask you
know, anybody catch Kate and ask her,
you know, for more detail on that as
well.
>> Isn't Isn't there a probate
[clears throat]
when someone dies? There's a probate and
they're supposed to pay back, you know,
any taxes or unpaid bills or
liens that I I thought
>> Well, I I would think the car goes to
somebody else.
>> But yeah, but there's still taxes when
you go through probate. Like my mother
Well, I'll get into it. Never mind.
>> Yeah, I agree with what Bill's saying.
Like you have to settle the estate and
that's
>> You have to settle the estate. Like I
had to settle my father's estate. He
died 8 years ago. My mother I got power
of attorney, put her in a home. So, I
had to
I had to go through probate and make
sure
there was no outstanding taxes or bills
or liens or whatever else. I'm surprised
that there's this much
of this that has never gone before
probate. I guess is my surprise.
>> Yeah, like if you have a credit card
before you can collect from the estate,
you have to pay off that balance.
>> Exactly.
>> Normally, a judge wants all bills paid.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> So, there's a question of whether the
judge knew about it.
You know, we do it all the time.
>> Gordon, it was just a lot of money.
>> [laughter]
>> And And it could be that there's
This only lists the primary. If it's say
like Matt and Carla Streeter have a
Subaru and and the bill comes to Matt
Streeter and Matt passes away, but she
still has the car and didn't pay the
taxes or something like that. Could be
that there are other mechanisms for why
these uh
uh perhaps didn't or
they were given to another kid and went
out of state. So, but let me check with
uh Kate and try and get a more coherent
answer for you for next meeting.
>> Sounds good. Thank you.
>> Sorry, you guys haven't voted yet.
>> No, we haven't, but I was going to just
see if anybody had further discussion
and then I'll proceed to call for vote.
Everybody good at this point? I think
that was a good chat.
>> [gasps and laughter]
>> Um all right, so I'll go around then uh
to take the vote here. Uh Liz.
>> Oh, yes.
>> I'm next on my screen, so I'll vote yes.
Nick.
Unmute yourself, sir.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you, Louise.
>> Heather.
>> Yes.
>> Bill.
>> Kim.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you. That is unanimous. Motion
passes. We can have our tax collector do
proceed uh along these lines. Excellent.
Uh let's see.
Liaison reports. Well, we
Yeah, as we discussed we we discussed
the school thing already. I think that's
the only liaison uh issue unless anybody
else has anything. I don't We didn't
have CIP.
So, um
I don't have anything to report from
Capital Improvement Committee.
We would
Given that, unless anybody has anything
uh further, then we would move on to our
long-standing meeting minute
approvals.
>> I read them.
>> Huzzah.
>> I read them, too, but Liz is the expert.
I'm telling you right now, if she says
yes, I'm a yes.
>> [laughter]
>> Did we go through the check register?
Did I miss it?
>> Oh, I'm sorry. I did sort of melt them
together with
a bunch of tax. Well, did you want to go
back and talk about the um
>> I had another question. I couldn't
remember what
Sirma Sirma something like that.
T I R
>> Sirma is the insurance carrier.
>> That's the insurance. That's um Karma, I
think that's property casualty insurance
liability insurance.
>> And workman's comp.
>> Work comp, liability, yep.
>> Yeah. Okay, I thought so. I couldn't
remember I thought it was some sort of
insurance. Okay.
>> Yeah, it's one of those acronyms for a
for
>> Connecticut interlocal
regional municipal,
yeah.
>> Consortium.
>> Thank you.
>> What was I had one on that one too.
What's Casella waste? I don't know if we
>> Transfer station.
>> Is that for the the dumping the um the
picking up of
>> It's it's it's for it's for when with
they when they come and take the uh the
the
the solid waste, the recycling,
>> [snorts]
>> bottles, cans, all those things. They go
to Casella and then we get charged a
rate for those tipping fees.
>> Tipping fees. That's That's the thing I
was trying to remember.
>> Technical term.
>> Yes. Yes. Like
Like the thing you asked about earlier
that I didn't know either.
>> Yeah, I was looking to E F T P S.
>> Electronic funds transfer.
>> Oh yes, thank you.
>> for the payroll and the taxes.
>> Yep.
>> Got it. And then
uh
I was just curious about a Janelco.
It was $514.93.
>> What's the date on that?
>> Find out for you.
>> Or the check number.
My report's at the office, but I've got
my laptop.
>> Oh.
I could
May 8th, Janelco 5704.
Janelco check number 13396.
Thank you.
That is the cost of printing and mailing
the either the town meeting or the
referendum notice.
Okay. Yeah, okay. So, we outsourced And
you're going to you're going to see that
multiple times.
Yes.
Okay. I just wanted to get my names down
so I Thanks, Deb.
Yeah, no problem.
Actually, no, I lied.
It's the one underneath. First time
ever.
No, I don't lie.
Um I apologize. Guillermo Printer is the
one that we do. Oh, yeah. Let me look up
Janelco. Janelco, I don't know. Let me
look.
Says vehicle parts, hydraulic fittings,
plow.
Oh, okay. That makes sense cuz it was
right by a Dubai Automotive one. Okay.
It sounds like we It sounds on a Yeah,
working on a machine. I mean, a vehicle.
Okay. That goes through the public works
account. Yeah. Public works, yep. That'd
be a public works question. Yeah. When I
was looking at the check, it seems like
there's some helpful notes in the memo
section, but it seems like that memo is
getting chopped.
I don't know if that's something we
could It's QuickBooks, and then I can
extend it and look at it, but it won't
let me print that.
Oh, that's not good. Yeah. So, it goes
away when you print.
I can try it landscape instead of
portrait and see if I can get any more
if you want.
That would looks like. No,
that that you're you're Nick, I was
thinking the same thing. It like you
like for Kerma, we have to put in the
memo insurance.
And it you know, it it can be in there.
And and Lisa, it it the problem probably
is if there's multiple bills and and the
check is paying multiple bills, it might
not come up, but we we can do that. Some
of that will come up.
>> It's uh uh
>> It's actually gotten much better because
much better.
>> Much better.
>> In the past there was no memos. And I
making a real point and so is Brenda to
try and fit whatever we can in there.
So, when you pull it up and when this
prints, there's an explanation in there.
>> Yeah, cuz it helps. It kind of just
gives me a good idea of what it is.
>> Yeah, it it it helps us avoid asking,
you know, something we've already asked
or you know, remember how we had like
multiple
questions about spring?
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, right.
>> Yes, because that's the insurance.
>> And we we we have the answer now. We
don't need to know spring it.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. I will say though, you know, Jeff,
I'm looking at this, but is that the
check for 24,000?
>> [clears throat]
>> Right?
>> Which one?
>> The the Kerma check was for 24,000.
>> Mhm.
>> 24,785.
>> Yeah, cuz in the description of the
bills, we put in there lap insurance
premium, workers comp insurance premium.
>> Mhm.
>> But will it go on the memo of the Will
[snorts] it print in the register even
if I put it in the memo of the check?
>> Mhm. Well, the question is do we put it
on both memos? You know how sometimes
you
If you put it in one memo, it comes up
in one spot and you got to Brenda's been
very good about putting it in in both
memos and then it comes through.
I mean, listen, and this information
needs to be um
uh
We need to find it.
>> that yeah, down at the bottom.
>> Okay.
>> It's not there. It's on the memo of the
invoice bill itself.
>> Okay.
>> And and Nick, I think we can I think we
can get with the finance department and
make that happen. It's just how it all
fits together. It's you know, does it
need to be in both the memos and then
the report comes out this way cuz you
know,
I would also probably want to provide
you guys
you know, I as I look at this like if
you look at the Comcast bill that would
the check that was written on 5/8
it says uh
DPW internet. Those are things that
should be in the memo. It should be like
hey, this is a
for this department. You know, like if
you were looking at QDS on here when QDS
gets paid, those are either tax
collector or
uh assessor's office and we should find
a way to put in the memo a way for you
guys to see that and understand it so
that you become more familiar with these
vendors as
uh the finance department is paying
them.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah, like when
particularly the smaller ones cuz I know
I go for the bigger ones when I'm
reading the list. But the smaller ones
it would help to just kind of know what
they're for.
And like I'm seeing some good stuff in
the memo but it it gets cut off. Like
the first one is attorney Dennis O'Brien
and it says quantity three.
>> That
That might be I Jeff that might be I
might be able to do that landscape. That
might be an answer to that. If the memo
is there.
>> I think it's a different report
honestly.
>> What I've had luck with
with formatting that is
I I have to do some similar things for
work. I print it legal on legal paper
and I do a print to PDF and then I
rotate it and it comes out I play a game
with it. But if it thinks it's printing
on a legal paper and then you rotate it
it kind of it looks a little interesting
in the PDF but it comes out so you could
read it.
>> That has never occurred to me to try
that, Nick. That's interesting. So, it's
almost like a pseudo landscape cuz
you're using a longer sheet and then
you're flipping it?
>> Yeah.
>> Interesting.
>> So, it gives you a bigger
essentially gives you a huge
playground for that data to sit on. So,
I print to computer and then I move it
in and it's like tricky to read, but you
can zoom in on it when it's electronic.
>> Mhm.
>> Sometime. [clears throat]
>> Yeah, Nick, I actually do the same thing
with my work. It works. Print to PDF.
>> Yep. Yeah, print to PDF is great. I just
never thought about using till I get to
legal paper to to kind of trick it.
That's interesting.
>> Yeah.
>> Very inventive, sir.
>> Tabloid [clears throat] if you want even
bigger. Yes, it gives you options.
>> Yeah, 11 by 17, baby.
Uh
All right, cool. Good to know.
So, uh while we're on the topic, is
there anything further on the
check register
that we want to chat about?
>> Just I have a question that's I'm sure
I don't know.
5 8 at the bottom, office of the
treasurer.
Is that a payment to the treasurer's
office for 3,766?
>> The Connecticut treasurer's office, not
my office.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> Yeah. Cuz you All of All of your
departments all have reports, whether
it's department inlands, clerk's office.
Uh They often have all these reports
they have to send to the
all these different departments. The
clerk's office must have four different
Connecticut state offices that we have
to send fees to. So, they do a monthly
report and then we have to send it in.
So, I would have to look.
>> What What is the check number on that
one?
>> Uh it's 13412.
It was 3,766.
Yeah, state of It does it say it says
office of the treasurer state of
Connecticut.
>> Yeah, well all of yeah, on the page all
I see is office of the truck.
>> Yeah, this is from the clerk's office on
mortgage releases.
>> Okay.
Thank you.
>> Yeah.
I'm good.
>> Good.
Okay.
Do we want to talk about meeting minutes
then?
>> Yes.
>> Eight, A through G.
>> [laughter]
>> Should we go through one at
one at a time?
Did anybody else read them or
>> I read some of them. I didn't finish.
>> I did I didn't have a chance but um I'm
I'm relying on you.
>> I said to myself, self, I better get
this done.
We got to get [laughter] this done.
So if we want to go April 8th,
um
it looked fine to me. I would make a
motion to accept uh the April 8th, 2026
meeting minutes.
>> I'll second that.
Was that you, Bill?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, thanks. Sorry, I'm scrolling and I
don't I don't
can't see. Okay.
Very good. We have that motion before
us. Uh any further discussion?
Take vote. Okay. Uh let's go in reverse
order. Louise.
>> Yes.
>> Kim.
>> Okay. Bill.
>> Yes.
>> Heather.
>> Nick.
>> Yes.
>> I'm a yes and Liz.
>> Is a yes.
Okay. Motion passes unanimously.
>> [gasps]
>> Next date.
>> April 9th.
>> April 9th. I see it.
>> Uh this looked fine by me.
I would make a motion to accept these
minutes
for April 9th, 2026.
It was the annual budget meeting.
>> It was the first budget meeting, right?
Yeah.
>> Yep. The town of And- Andover annual
budget meeting in the school gym.
>> Indeed.
>> I'll second that.
>> Louise seconds. Excellent.
Very good.
Uh, go around.
Um,
Nick.
>> Yes.
>> Heather.
>> Phil.
>> Yes.
>> Kim.
>> Louise.
>> Yes.
>> Liz.
>> And yes. That's everybody. Motion passes
unanimously.
Okay, so that's the 9th. Great. That
brings us to the 22nd?
April 22nd?
>> The 22nd.
Um, so I had the questions I had about
this one.
If you go down to new business the new
business section,
>> Yep.
>> discuss discussing possibly create
meeting minutes from the unrecorded 325.
>> Yep.
>> I had I had emailed everybody
and I think I heard from Heather
and Rob
and
I don't know if that's part of this
or not.
>> Oh.
Oh, I
I
well,
hm.
>> Should be added in, shouldn't they?
>> Or no?
>> Well, it it should be a
So, that email I forwarded it to myself
again, so it's up at the top of my
emails again. Basically, we need to look
at that and
we probably should have added
the agenda.
>> Discuss and possibly create meeting
minutes from unrecorded 325 special
budget meeting discussed
discussed recording not started.
Um,
>> Yep.
>> I mean, I suppose we can accept this.
>> Yeah.
>> And we can decide to
maybe add that
special
BOS I think that was a special meeting
at the beginning with the board of
selectmen.
>> think it was that first it was that
first hour. Yes, 6:00 to 7:00 joint
meeting.
>> Yep.
>> Um which, you know, believe me, I'm
still kicking myself for not pressing
the button.
>> That's okay.
>> But yeah, maybe when we put through when
we have the 325-26 minutes put through,
we attach
something
>> Or it's just
I think maybe we we put that for next
month's agenda say add approval of that
of that and I will resend it.
Maybe I'll send it to Kate and have her
prepare it and send it to us as part of
next month's
uh
>> Yeah, as proposed recreated 325-26
special budget meeting minutes.
>> to call it an addendum to those minutes?
Um something like that.
>> Huh?
>> An addendum?
>> actually No, it's actually it's actually
the
the meeting minutes. It's a recreation
of the meeting minutes because the the
meeting wasn't recorded.
>> Right, first meeting. Yeah.
>> So the meeting taker was not able to
take the minutes. So it's actually a
separate meeting minute.
Um
>> Right.
>> That's never been uploaded.
And it really needs to be uploaded.
>> These minutes can be approved and then
the 6:00 meetings' minutes can be
forwarded to all of us to approve at the
next meeting.
Right.
>> Yeah, that's what I'm doing.
>> Yeah, I agree I agree with that plan.
There we go.
>> Okay.
>> that plan.
So do we need to You otherwise Were you
otherwise fine with these with this um
>> Um I think so.
Yeah, I think I think so.
Yeah,
I'm fine with that. It looks okay. Yeah,
I'm just looking at it. It looks
Mhm.
It's okay to me. Yep. It looked okay to
me.
Okay. So I would make a motion
to accept the April 22nd
regular meeting minutes.
Thank you Liz.
Do we have a second?
Second. Great. Bill seconds.
All right.
Let's go around. Liz.
Yes. Tim. Yes. Bill. Yes. Heather. Yes.
Nick. Yes. Moi, yes. Liz. Yes. Yes. 7-0.
Motion passes. Budgets, sorry, meetings
minutes accepted.
That brings us to Wednesday, April 29th,
I believe. Yeah.
So on the first page, number three,
number
three, the second paragraph,
the third line up where it says
substantial completing. Can somebody
read that and tell me if it makes sense
because Sorry, is this the paragraph
that starts with your name? Yeah, it's
the bottom three lines. Substantial
Substantial completing.
It should be substantial complete,
shouldn't it? Substantially completed
with time prior to
completed
with time prior reopening to complete
punch list items.
That's an odd sentence. Yeah, it's a
it's a What it is is a phase of a
project. Substantial completion. Okay.
So that's that's that's the word
substantial completion. I think it
should be completion.
So we should amend completing to
completion. Right. Okay.
Okay, my brain wasn't on wasn't firing
when I
was reading that. Like what happened?
Yeah, no, it doesn't make sense like
that, but it is a phase of a project.
So, substantial completion.
>> with time prior to school reopening to
complete punch list items. That makes
sense.
>> Yep.
>> Uh that was the only thing I saw on
that.
>> So, we I would make the motion with that
correction, we accept these minutes.
From substantial to substantial sub-
Yeah, from
substantial completion.
>> We wanted to say substantial completion.
Yes.
>> Substantial completion is what I want to
say.
>> Indeed.
>> [laughter]
>> Hopefully hopefully Kate gets that. All
right, so
um do we have a second?
Or did we wait? Do we have a motion?
>> I made the motion with that change.
>> Okay. You made the motion with the
change. Liz seconds.
>> I'll second it.
>> Oh, Liz Louise seconds, sorry.
>> Yeah, I second it.
>> All right. Uh we'll take take a vote.
Liz?
>> Yes.
>> I'm a yes.
>> Heather?
>> Yes.
>> Bill?
>> Nick?
>> Yes.
>> Kim?
>> And Louise?
>> Yes.
>> 7-0. Great. With that one change, that
one's done.
That gets us to May 6th.
>> May 6th.
>> workshop.
>> Special budget So, page three of XX,
that footer needs to be fixed.
That should be five. Page three of five.
>> There on on literally on page three. On
the other pages, it's fine.
>> Yes. Yep. It's just It's little things.
>> The footer on page three, yep.
>> Yep. And then I did not re-listen to
this meeting, but I think this might be
incorrect. If you go to page four, the
second paragraph,
when we talked about the end goal to get
somewhere between 3 to 4%, blah blah
blah, Rob second in the motion seconded
motion carries with Liz, Heather, and
Louise voting no.
I don't know if that's
>> I think it was probably Liz
Liz and Kim.
>> That's what I think and I did not go
back and listen to it and verify it but
I'm pretty sure.
>> sure as well.
Uh that's my that is also my
recollection.
>> Everybody agree with that
Heather do you agree with that?
>> I'm trying to think um
Well this was when we cut it to we cut
it $50,000 at initial
>> cut. Yeah the first small cut.
>> Oh yeah I think I I think I
>> You were on the yes side.
>> I was on the yes side I think.
>> You were too.
>> Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
So we should so we have two changes
right now on this one the footer on page
three
and it's instead of Liz Heather and
Louise voting no it's Liz Kim and Louise
voting no
on the second paragraph of page four.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> With those changes I would make a motion
to put the May 6th special budget
workshop minutes to accept those minutes
with those changes
just
reported.
>> Second.
>> Bill seconds. Great.
Very good.
Uh Kim.
>> Yes.
>> Louise.
>> Nick.
>> Yes.
>> Bill.
>> Heather.
>> Yes.
>> Me yes and Liz.
>> All right excellent.
Motion passes
unanimously unanimously gets us to May
27th.
>> And then on the first page of May 27th
um
under the public speak Scott Soyatt this
sentence doesn't
doesn't really make sense either.
>> Oh I think what it should say is uh
didn't see Scott didn't think that the
results of the
referendum
were a band-aid to make to cut AAS
budget deeply. Right? So it says right
now don't want to see results mandate
cut to AAS budget deeply. I would say
what he as I recall his comment, he did
not see the results of the
referendum as a mandate to cut the AAS
budget deeply. That's the way it seems.
>> So didn't see results as a mandate.
>> Right.
>> I can confirm.
I can confirm that's what I meant.
>> [laughter]
>> He's not on the line. He's on the ball,
so.
>> Yeah, right.
>> Very good. Thank you, Scott.
>> AAS budget with tutor. Okay.
All right. So for the for the recording
I'll say it out loud again.
Didn't
see the results
as a mandate to cut AAS budget deeply.
>> Results of referendum. Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> Yes.
Okay. So with that change
That was the only one.
Yeah, with that I would make a motion to
accept May 27th
2026 regular meeting minutes.
>> I'll second.
>> Louise seconds. Excellent.
Very good. Uh
go around. I'll take it from the top
this time. Liz.
>> Yes.
>> I'm a yes as well, Heather.
>> Bill.
>> Yes.
>> Nick.
>> Kim.
>> Yes.
>> Louise.
>> Yes, and thank you, Liz. I want to thank
Liz for all that.
>> Oh, yes. Thank you.
>> For all the examination.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, that's fine.
That's fine. I had a little bit of time,
so.
>> Oh my gosh, we're at the last one. It's
a miracle.
>> It's the last one.
>> [laughter]
>> And I have to abstain from this one cuz
I wasn't here.
>> This is a bit This was a tough one. This
one
>> Yes.
>> Uh this was our setting the mill rate.
And um
that looks right to me.
So I will go ahead and move that
we approve uh
the meeting minutes Wednesday, June 17th
special budget meeting.
>> I'll second that. [snorts]
>> Thanks, Olivia.
>> That was a quick meeting.
>> It was, thank goodness. It was a work It
was a work day for some of us.
>> Okay.
>> Uh all right, very good. Um so um Liz
wasn't here, she was away. Um
much deserved, I'm sure. So she'll be
off of this one, so I'll start with
Heather.
>> Yes.
>> Very good, Bill.
>> Nick.
>> Yes.
>> Kim.
>> Louise.
>> Yes.
>> And I'm a yes. That's 6-0. Motion
passes.
>> abstain. Yeah.
>> Yes. And you Oh, you know, I'm sorry.
>> abstain.
>> Thank you.
Apologies.
Uh
I was so hard to try to get through it.
Okay, very good. That concludes section
eight of our
um
>> agenda
>> agenda. That brings us to board open
discussion. If anybody has anything
further at this time, um
I
feel like we've had We've talked about a
lot, but if you've got anything to bring
up, this is the time to do it.
Okay, hearing none.
Um
correspondence.
Uh I'm behind on my emails. I can't
think of anything in particular.
Um
but I have I like I said, I'm behind on
my emails.
>> [laughter]
>> I have to get through it.
Um anybody else have anything they want
to bring forward? If not,
we can go on to public speak.
>> Perfect.
>> Okay.
Very good. Public speak. It looks like
we've got one, two, three at least. So
we'll start I'll just go in order of
who's on my screen. Scott, you're up.
>> I have nothing to Thank you.
>> Thanks. Joanne, you're up.
>> Yeah, a couple of quick things. Um, I
understand the need to, you know, have
the better payroll system. I just
thought from listening to all the
meetings you were going to be purchasing
out of next year's budget. So, obviously
there might have been money left over,
so they went ahead and got it started in
June cuz I thought that, you know, so I
just wanted to note that for the meeting
since it crossed my mind. And then the
other quick thing that crossed my mind,
too, um,
and thank you for bringing it up, Rob.
Um, when talking about the contract
negotiations, and I know the town will
be undergoing that, and you know, that
takes a little time, and it's important
to have,
you know, a good contract negotiation
presented from management versus
the employees. The only thing I was
going to say is that that Rob had
brought up the fee in lieu of,
you know, thing
>> The in lieu of the health insurance.
>> Yeah, exactly. And I know, you know, for
the public and putting it out there on
the meeting, that it has gone back and
forth in emails for about 3 years now,
that it was going to be looked at, and
that, you know, the price has gotten
staggering for the town. And if the town
is, you know, contributing about 35,000
or so, and I'm not privy to what you all
see, just from, you know, that's gotten
really, really high. That money could be
spent I don't expect any employee that
gets it to ever want to say anything
negative about it. Why would they? It's
a great, you know, it's a great feature
for them. But, um, but, you know, it's
it's you've talked about, you know, I
have a good memory for all these
meetings. So, you know, you've talked
about capping it. You've talked about,
you know, we're the only town that get
has such a high, high thing, and we're
such a small town. Um, then it's been
talked about, well, if we don't do this,
um, I just feel like it's important to
say this tonight cuz if you're these
contract negotiations will be done
before you know it. I, you know, I know
how Andover goes. But um, you know, you
think about well, if we don't do this
for the employees, then they're going to
take the insurance, so we're saving
money. As someone that works in HR, that
does payroll, that does it,
there's a cost to taking health
insurance. The The employee has to put
out about 14 to whatever it's at. And
with these staggering plans that we have
now, I get it. That's a high amount to
just put out. So,
I don't think the employees will just
take it. So, I hope that Andover, you
know, talks about it and and you know,
in this negotiation that has to kind of
encompass the whole town, the policy
book, it's finally time, you know, after
now that these
things are going to increase, increase,
increase. And then the other thing, and
I I just as someone that
looks at conflicts of interests and
people being on committees, you do have
someone that you've had join that
committee tonight that has family
members that are affected. I don't know
if that's a good look. Listen, everybody
that volunteers to be on committees are
good, but if you're going to vote on
something that employee receives or
doesn't receive, you just might want to
have someone else have that post, you
know. It It's just a conflict of
interest. We don't do it in my town and
have anybody that has a relative or
someone. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Joanne.
>> I Yeah, I didn't mean to go on and on.
It's just important for this tonight.
I'm really hoping this is the year that
Andover does it, but
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you. Um, and I I hadn't considered
that last point. All right, um,
next public comment will be Elizabeth
Partridge.
>> I have no comment at this point. Thank
you.
>> Thank you.
All right.
Uh, let's see. Where does that bring us?
>> Got Scott, yet?
>> I did, Scott.
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
>> with him. He said he had nothing.
>> Okay.
>> I went I went the other I went who's in
my screen.
>> I got you.
>> So, do we have a motion to adjourn?
>> I'll make the motion to adjourn.
>> I
>> What what's up, Bill?
>> Sorry, Bill.
>> Well, I was just wondering based on what
Joanne just said, should we address
as a board first the member that she has
a conflict with and
and nothing against that that person.
I'm just saying is it a valid point and
should we consider it and B, should we
have a
talking points for those negotiations
that the Board of
Finance would like to see discussed in
those discussion. We're just going to
put it out there and leave it.
But, should we have some kind of a a
plan going into those discussions?
>> What I'm not sure what conflict of
interest we're talking about.
>> We're talking about a town employee
>> Town employee.
>> related uh
>> to Kim.
>> to Kim. uh
>> I I would This is Matt. I would just say
let's I would not want to have any
discussions on this public meeting if
we're talking about
strategies for negotiations at this
point in juncture. I think that we could
talk about
I can have a one-on-one conversation
with Rob about maybe trying to set up
something. But, I but to to go into
details at this point might be I don't
want to say premature, but also you'll
get tip our hand in some ways. So,
>> All right.
>> Thank you.
>> I just wanted
Yeah, I just wanted to say to clarify
this since you asked the question. It's
just if you have a family member that
works in a in an organization, you you
probably shouldn't be on the committee
that's going to decide wages and things
like that. I'm not I'm with Matt. You
don't discuss it publicly. I just mean
who's going to comprise the committee.
That's all.
>> I mean when I agreed to do this, it was
to learn more about
the contracts and the union and
that is solely it. My role here on the
Board of Finance is to represent the
town.
>> Court.
>> If it
>> I think it's probable.
>> then
>> conflict
>> I can pass it off to somebody else.
>> I don't mind doing it or or even doing
it together with Kim.
I don't know how you all feel about
that.
>> It
>> Fine.
>> Yeah, I'm not clear on who's in what
union. So and I this is obviously a
tricky situation.
Uh and it's and uh
>> I'm not either, Rob.
>> What?
>> Okay.
>> Should we get um
should we get Dennis involved in this?
>> No. If
let's find out who the who's in which
union and if Joanne is correct, I would
sit there and say let let's do it.
And Kim, it's no it's nothing on you.
It's just let's let's
not have it.
>> Avoid the even the appearance.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> I completely agree.
>> All right, great. Let's let's sort that.
Who's in what union? If it's applicable,
Liz, thanks for stepping up. You're a
backup.
Uh otherwise you'll be kept. Fantastic.
Thanks for that. I appreciate it, guys.
And you know what? Good to bring that
up, Joanne. It completely slipped my
mind. All right.
>> [clears throat]
>> Anything further or should we adjourn?
>> I'll make a motion on the floor.
Oh. Oh, we have a Yes.
I made a motion to adjourn.
>> Thank you, Louise.
>> Second. I'll second.
>> At the same time. Who second?
Liz.
>> Liz.
>> All right. In favor, uh let's go around.
Uh Bill.
>> Yes.
>> Heather.
>> Yep.
>> Dick.
>> Yes.
>> Louise?
>> Pam?
>> Yes.
>> Liz?
>> And I'm also a yes, therefore the
meeting the motion passes the meeting's
adjourned. Thank you everybody,
appreciate it.
>> Thank you.
>> Appreciate the volunteers, appreciate
all the information.
And I'm going to stop the recording.
Have a good night.
>> Good night everyone.
>> Bye-bye.
>> Good night.